Hello, English learners.
你好，英语学习者。
Welcome back to EnglishPod.
欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And today we're bringing you the sequel of I'm Sorry I Love You.
今天我们为大家带来《对不起，我爱你》的续集。
Part two.
第二部分。
That's right.
没错。
I guess a lot of our listeners enjoyed the first part.
我想很多听众都很喜欢第一部分。
And since it was such a romantic dialogue and hit, we're bringing part two.
而且因为它是一个浪漫的对话，反响很好，所以我们带来了第二部分。
So it's even more romantic and I'm sure everyone is going to find some great and useful language
所以它更加浪漫，我相信每个人都能找到一些很棒且有用的语言
in it.
在里面。
That's right.
没错。
And it's the language that we use to talk about dates.
而且这是我们用来谈论约会的语言。
A date, yeah.
约会，是的。
So useful language for when you're going on a date.
所以当你去约会时，这些语言很有用。
That's right.
没错。
Well, before we look at this date language, let's listen to the dialogue for the first
在我们看这些约会语言之前，让我们先听一遍对话。
time.
第一次。
I'm so relieved that your ankle wasn't broken.
我很庆幸你的脚踝没有骨折。
I feel just awful about this whole thing.
我对整件事感到非常抱歉。
I want to make it up to you.
我想补偿你。
Let me take you out to dinner tonight, my treat.
让我今晚带你出去吃饭，我请客。
Oh, that sounds great.
哦，听起来不错。
I'd love to.
我很乐意。
Here's my address.
这是我的地址。
Pick me up at eight.
八点来接我。
Perfect.
完美。
Thank you for such a lovely evening.
谢谢你给了我这么美好的夜晚。
The food was amazing and I had a great time.
食物很棒，我玩得很开心。
Me too.
我也是。
You look so beautiful tonight.
你今晚真美。
I wish this night would never end.
我希望这个夜晚永远不会结束。
There's something that I have to tell you.
有件事我必须告诉你。
But what is it?
是什么？
I woke up today thinking that this would be just like any other day.
今天醒来时，我以为这会是平常的一天。
But I was wrong.
但我错了。
A twist of fate brought us together.
命运的转折让我们相遇。
I crashed into your life and you into mine.
我闯入了你的生活，你也闯入了我的。
And this may sound crazy, but I'm falling in love with you, Veronica.
这听起来可能很疯狂，但我爱上你了，Veronica。
Wow, such a romantic dialogue.
哇，真是浪漫的对话。
It really sounds like they're falling in love.
听起来他们真的在相爱。
Yeah, it's a really romantic thing that's going on right now, but there were some really
是啊，现在发生的事情真的很浪漫，但这里有一些非常
useful words here, so why don't we take a look at language takeaway?
有用的词汇，所以我们来看看语言要点吧？
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
Today we have three words for language takeaway.
今天我们有三个语言要点的单词。
And the first one is relieved.
第一个是 relieved。
Relieved.
Relieved。
So, we have some great examples on how we use relieved and I'm really sure you can understand
所以，我们有一些很好的例子来说明如何使用 relieved，我相信你一定能理解。
the meaning from the sentences.
从句子中理解意思。
Example one.
例子一。
They were relieved to hear that the company would not be making any layoffs.
他们听到公司不会裁员，松了一口气。
Example two.
例子二。
I'm so relieved to hear your voice.
听到你的声音，我真是松了一口气。
I was worried something happened to you.
我担心你出了什么事。
I guess relieved is like a happy or relaxed feeling that you get if you avoid something
我想“relieved”就像是一种快乐或放松的感觉，当你避免了一些不好的事情时。
bad, right?
对吧？
Right.
对。
I'm so relieved that didn't happen.
我很庆幸那没有发生。
Yeah.
是的。
Now for our second word, pick me up.
现在来看第二个词，接我。
Pick me up.
接我。
So when you ask someone to pick you up, you're saying basically...
所以当你让别人来接你时，你基本上是在说……
Come and get me.
过来接我。
Okay, so let's give a couple of examples.
好的，我们来举几个例子。
My husband was supposed to pick me up from work yesterday, but he forgot.
我丈夫昨天应该来接我下班的，但他忘了。
Does that really happen?
真的会发生这种事吗？
Yes.
是的。
All right, we'll have a talk with him.
好的，我们会和他谈谈。
Or we could also say, oh, I need to hurry up.
或者我们也可以说，哦，我得快点。
The taxi will pick me up at seven.
出租车七点来接我。
Yes.
是的。
So come and get me.
所以来接我吧。
Right.
对。
Pick me up.
来接我。
And our final word in today's language takeaway is...
今天语言学习的最后一个词是……
Ordinary.
普通的。
So, ordinary is a normal word.
所以，ordinary 是一个普通的词。
Yes, meaning?
是的，意思是？
It's normal.
就是正常的意思。
Uh-huh.
嗯哼。
Nothing uncommon about it.
没什么特别的。
Yeah.
对。
So you can have like an ordinary person.
所以你可以说一个普通人。
An ordinary day.
普通的一天。
Ordinary life.
普通的生活。
Uh-huh.
嗯哼。
Nothing exciting about it.
没什么令人兴奋的。
What else is ordinary?
还有什么东西是普通的？
Ordinary podcast.
普通的播客。
An ordinary podcast, which English pod is not.
一个普通的播客，但 English Pod 可不是。
Is not.
不是。
Okay.
好的。
Yeah.
对。
So ordinary.
所以，ordinary。
Okay, great words.
好的，很好的词。
And I guess now we can listen to our dialogue a second time.
我想我们现在可以再听一遍对话了。
This time it'll be a little bit slower, and this will help you to understand the language
这次会慢一点，这样能帮助你更清楚地理解语言。
more clearly.
更清楚。
I'm so relieved that your ankle wasn't broken.
我很庆幸你的脚踝没有骨折。
I feel just awful about this whole thing.
我对整件事感到非常抱歉。
I want to make it up to you.
我想补偿你。
Let me take you out to dinner tonight.
今晚让我带你出去吃饭吧。
My treat.
我请客。
That sounds great.
听起来不错。
I'd love to.
我很乐意。
Here is my address.
这是我的地址。
Pick me up at eight?
八点来接我？
Perfect.
完美。
Thank you for such a lovely evening.
谢谢你让我度过了一个如此愉快的夜晚。
The food was amazing, and I had a great time.
食物很棒，我玩得很开心。
Me too.
我也是。
You look so beautiful tonight.
你今晚看起来真美。
I wish this night would never end.
我希望这个夜晚永远不会结束。
There's something I have to tell you.
有件事我得告诉你。
What is it?
什么事？
I woke up today thinking this would be just like any other ordinary day, but I was wrong.
今天醒来时，我以为这会是又一个普通的日子，但我错了。
A twist of fate brought us together.
命运的转折让我们相遇。
I crashed into your life and you into mine, and this may sound crazy, but I'm falling
我闯入了你的生活，你也闯入了我的生活，这听起来可能很疯狂，但我已经
in love with you, Veronica.
爱上你了，维罗妮卡。
Okay, so we looked at some great vocabulary, and now we can look at some great phrases,
好了，我们看了一些很棒的词汇，现在可以看一些很棒的短语了。
so let's start with Fluency Builder.
让我们从流利度构建器开始。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建器。
On Fluency Builder today we have three great phrases, so why don't we just start with the
今天的流利度构建器中有三个很棒的短语，我们就从第一个开始吧。
first one?
第一个吗？
Yeah, the first one we heard at the beginning of the dialogue.
是的，就是我们在对话开头听到的第一个。
Make it up to you.
补偿你。
Okay, so we have some great examples on how we use make it up, so let's listen.
好的，我们有一些关于如何使用“make it up”的好例子，我们来听听。
Example one.
例子一。
I'm sorry I forgot your birthday.
对不起，我忘了你的生日。
How can I make it up to you?
我该怎么补偿你？
Example two.
例子二。
I feel terrible for calling your mother fat.
我因为说你妈妈胖而感到很糟糕。
I want to make it up to her, so I got her these flowers.
我想补偿她，所以给她买了这些花。
Example three.
例子三。
John forgot my anniversary again.
约翰又忘了我们的纪念日。
He's going to have to make it up to me.
他得补偿我。
We can see from the examples that when you use the phrase make it up to you, you're kind
从这些例子中我们可以看出，当你使用“补偿你”这个短语时，你有点
of saying you want to balance something bad you did with some good action, right?
像是在说你想用一些好的行为来平衡你做过的坏事，对吧？
Right, so if you call your mother-in-law fat.
对，所以如果你说你岳母胖。
You better buy her at least some flowers or a card or something.
你最好至少给她买些花或一张卡片之类的。
To make it up, right?
来补偿，对吧？
Yeah.
嗯。
So the bad action was?
那么不好的行为是什么？
Calling her fat.
说她胖。
And the balancing good action was the flowers.
而弥补的好行为是送花。
Yeah.
嗯。
I don't think flowers will be enough though.
不过我觉得光送花还不够。
Looks like a doomed marriage.
看来这婚姻没救了。
Okay, our second phrase.
好了，我们的第二个短语。
My treat.
我请客。
So we use this phrase when we want to say I'll invite you, I'll pay for you.
所以当我们想说我来邀请你、我来付钱时，就用这个短语。
I'll pay.
我来付。
Right, so I can say, hey, let's go get some beers.
对，所以我可以这么说：嘿，我们去喝点啤酒吧。
It's my treat.
我请客。
Oh, thanks, Marco.
哦，谢谢，马可。
So I'm paying, right?
所以是我付钱，对吧？
My treat.
我请客。
And our last phrase for fluency builder.
我们流利度训练部分的最后一个短语。
A twist of fate.
命运的转折。
So Erica, what is a twist of fate?
那么埃里卡，什么是命运的转折？
A twist of fate is an unplanned event that has a big impact on your future or your life.
命运的转折是一个计划外的事件，对你的未来或生活产生重大影响。
Okay.
好的。
Marco, can you give us an example of a twist of fate?
马可，你能给我们举一个命运转折的例子吗？
All right, for example.
好的，比如。
Okay, you're supposed to catch a flight to another country, all right?
好吧，你本来要赶飞机去另一个国家，对吧？
But you're late, so you miss your flight.
但你迟到了，所以错过了航班。
Okay.
好的。
And that flight crashes.
而那架飞机坠毁了。
Wow.
哇。
Right, so that's a twist of fate.
对，这就是命运的转折。
So yeah, it's like fate, it's like destiny.
所以是的，就像命运，就像天意。
You weren't supposed to be on that flight.
你本来就不该上那架飞机。
Okay, so a twist of fate.
好的，所以是命运的转折。
A twist of fate.
命运的转折。
Great.
太好了。
On a happier note, let's listen to the dialogue a third time.
说点开心的，让我们再听一遍对话。
I'm so relieved that your ankle wasn't broken.
我很庆幸你的脚踝没有骨折。
I feel just awful about this whole thing.
我对整件事感到非常抱歉。
I want to make it up to you.
我想补偿你。
Let me take you out to dinner tonight, my treat.
今晚让我带你出去吃饭，我请客。
Oh, that sounds great.
哦，听起来不错。
I'd love to.
我很乐意。
Here's my address.
这是我的地址。
Pick me up at eight?
八点来接我？
Perfect.
完美。
Thank you for such a lovely evening.
谢谢你让我度过这么美好的夜晚。
The food was amazing and I had a great time.
食物很棒，我玩得很开心。
Me too.
我也是。
You look so beautiful tonight.
你今晚看起来真美。
I wish this night would never end.
我希望这个夜晚永远不会结束。
There's something that I have to tell you.
有件事我得告诉你。
But what is it?
什么事？
I woke up today thinking that this would be just like any other day, but I was wrong.
今天醒来时，我以为这会是平凡的一天，但我错了。
The twist of fate brought us together.
命运的转折让我们相遇。
I crashed into your life and you into mine and this may sound crazy, but I'm falling
我闯入了你的生活，你也闯入了我的生活，这听起来可能很疯狂，但我正在
in love with you, Veronica.
爱上你，维罗妮卡。
Okay so we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
Erika, I know you have a story of a twist of fate in your life.
埃里卡，我知道你生活中有一个命运的转折故事。
Yes.
是的。
Recently, actually, this happened.
实际上，最近就发生了这样的事。
I went to this party and at the party there was a contest, like sort of a lottery.
我去参加了一个派对，派对上有一个比赛，有点像抽奖。
You could buy some tickets and win a prize and the prize was a week-long vacation.
你可以买些票来赢取奖品，奖品是一周的假期。
So I went with some friends of mine and they were tired so they left early and they gave
我和几个朋友一起去的，他们累了就先走了，并把
me their tickets.
他们的票给了我。
And guess what happened?
猜猜发生了什么？
What happened?
发生了什么？
We won.
我们赢了。
We won the week-long vacation.
我们赢得了一周的假期。
Wow.
哇。
Yeah, it was amazing.
是啊，太棒了。
So that was a really lucky twist of fate for me.
所以对我来说，这真是一个幸运的命运转折。
A lucky twist of fate.
一个幸运的命运转折。
That's a good story.
这是个好故事。
Yeah.
是啊。
I'm sure it wasn't that good of a twist of fate for your friends.
我敢肯定，对你的朋友们来说，这个命运转折可没那么好。
Yeah, but they were very generous and let me have the prize anyway.
是啊，但他们很大方，还是让我拿走了奖品。
All right.
好吧。
Well, we want to hear your stories of maybe some type of twist of fate that you've had.
我们想听听你们的故事，也许是一些你们经历过的命运转折。
Yes.
是的。
Maybe love stories, maybe tragic stories, any story.
也许是爱情故事，也许是悲剧故事，任何故事都行。
So be sure to leave your questions and comments and your stories at our website, EnglishPod.com
所以一定要在我们的网站 EnglishPod.com 上留下你们的问题、评论和故事，
and where you can also find us to answer any questions or doubts.
你也可以在那里找到我们，解答任何问题或疑惑。
Yes, that's right.
是的，没错。
So I guess until then, it's goodbye.
那么我想，直到下次，再见。